marques.catarina@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/catarina-mendes

Northampton, UK • 07922 003201

Digital Marketing Manager / Senior Executive

Creative, Marketing Professional with 15 years' international experience and 5 years' experience in B2B working in the IT sector. Keen enthusiast of UX/UI, design thinking and practices and marketing automation. Proven experience setting marketing goals, managing, articulating, and executing end to end tactical campaigns.

Boost brand awareness amongst targeted audiences, whilst driving quality traffic and increasing favourability amongst consumers by managing and executing marketing activities. Instrumental in increasing sales pipeline by gathering and analysing market data, translating analysis into marketing collateral. Shape, broaden, and sustain global channel, distribution, and reseller partnerships, whilst building sustainable industry networks.

- Event Management
- Channel Marketing (EMEA/APAC/US)
- Lead generation

- Marketing plans and strategy
- B₂B Marketing
- Marketing automation
- Content creation
- Public and Media relations
- Budget control

Career Experience

Appraisd 12/2021 to Present

Digital Marketing Manager (Permanent contract – currently working here!)

Responsible for redeveloping the organisation's marketing plan and executing all marketing activities. Managed freelance web-designers, design agencies and freelance content writers.

Key outcomes:

- Managed Appraisd rebrand including new visual identity, website migration and development, content revisit and development of new positioning
- Managed sales lead generation stages and collateral advising and implementing new processes to speed sales leads conversion

BSI, Cybersecurity and Information Resilience

02/2021 to 12/2021

Marketing Executive (Permanent contract)

Developed end to end content campaigns focused on targeting new prospects and increasing sales pipeline via thought leadership content, events and social media. Re-developed BSI's lead process by automating nurture workflows in Pardot/Salesforce to further qualify SQL's.

Key outcomes:

- Managed 400+ registrations lead generation webinar focusing on ransomware leading to over 150 qualified SQL's.
- Assisted in onboarding new technology partners to BSI technology partner solutions, working alongside BSI PR, Social and Channel Marketing teams.
- Developed new strategic content, focusing on emerging technologies and 5G, actively promoting BSI services to enterprise level prospects and customers.

Milton Keynes College 09/2020 to 02/2021

Workplace Trainer: Digital Marketing (Permanent contract)

Supported Level 3 Digital Marketing apprentices from onboarding to End Point Assessment (EPA). Instrumental in redesigning training materials for BCS Level 3 Certificate in Marketing Principles, which I've also taught during the Autumn 2020 Cohort. Mentoring and fostering relationships with apprentices and their employers, ensuring progress and delivery of the apprenticeship program

Page 2

Key outcomes:

- Managing employers and apprentices in sessions over Teams ensuing progress and successful completion of the apprenticeship.
- Guidance and mentoring of students in Marketing principles, theories, and tactics as well as report writing, public speaking and overall presentation of their individual portfolio.

JefferyM. Consulting, Northampton

04/2020 to 06/2020

Partner Engagement Manager (3 Months contract)

Support Partners in The Cloud Commercial Communities (CCC) division at Microsoft, assisting them in executing marketing, sales and technical benefits that include Social promotions, Press-releases, Case Studies and more.

Key outcomes:

- Effectively engaged and build relationships with Microsoft Technology partners in EMEA/APAC.
- Assisted partners commercial listings in Microsoft Azure and AppSource improve visibility and reach by providing feedback, and implementing changes, on their solution offerings considering target audiences, key value proposition, SEO tactics and formatting.
- Acting as the liaison between Microsoft Partner and other stakeholders (Microsoft PR team, publishing teams, etc.)
 ensuring partner execution of their benefits within the allocated timeframe (3 to 6 months) whilst ensuring these
 benefits aligned with the Partner's strategic plans.

Extensis, Northampton 10/2014 to 03/2020

International Marketing Specialist (Permanent contract – internal promotion – 9 months)

Planning and executing end-to-end marketing plans and campaigns for the EMEA region focusing on digital acquisition (attract new customers, cross-sell and nourishing existing customers). Ensuring all aspects of the campaigns are executed on time and within budget. Liaising with Content, Social, Design, or other internal teams, as well as 3rd party external vendors overseeing deliverables and successfully completion of tasks. Ensuring marketing KPI's are in place and presented quarterly to the Head of Marketing and EMEA Senior Sales team.

Key outcomes:

- Successfully planned and overseen lead generation campaigns specific to the EMEA region, resulting in a steady flow of new marketing qualified leads to the sales team.
- Supported sales team in increasing conversions by facilitating the development of costumer focused collateral and information that highlighted customer's key pain points and challenges ensuring relatability and facilitating on-to-one interaction with sales.
- Achieved stringent project deadlines and professional outcome whilst managing French and German portion of Extensis rebrand in 2019, which included overseeing translation, proofreading and liaising with Content and Web teams, to ensure professional and accurate look of the French/German versions of Extensis website (approx. 600 pages of new content).
- Improved communications with partners by launching programmes designed to strengthen channel sales strategy in partnership with channel sales manager.
- Transform the user experience through digital marketing, ensuring consistent, accurate messaging across email marketing, social media, and websites, subsequently heightening brand recognition.

Channel Marketing Specialist (Permanent contract – internal promotion – 1 year)

Instrumental in maximising sales in EMEA through programme development, marketing assets, and campaigns in direct support of global channel programme and EMEA business team. Leverage network of worldwide reseller and distribution partners to grow channel revenue, whilst promoting Extensis.

Page | 3

Key outcomes:

- Supported a partner in presenting Extensis digital asset solution to Spanish museums and galleries by co-hosting
 an informative webinar, defining promotional pricing strategy, formulated collateral, and organising follow-up
 information for sales team. Information provided team with additional insight into vertical, enabling the delivery
 of more effective sales in the Spanish market.
- Revitalised relationships with specific EMEA partners to formulate marketing programmes and expand promotions. New relationships led to:
 - Planning and executing follow up plan for an Italian partner after a successful event in Milan. Within the listed activities the plan included the creation of a webinar targeted to the event attendees. 60% of the event lead list registered for the webinar, despite this not being in their native language and registered into the subsequent lead nurturing program.
 - o Occasion to present new opportunities to partners to represent Extensis at regional industry events and support partners before, during, and after attending events and / or representing the company.

EMEA Marketing Co-Ordinator (Permanent contract – 3 years and 9 months)

Streamlined marketing of products and services throughout EMEA in alignment with overall marketing strategy, whilst identifying new opportunities within UK and European markets. Drove consumer interest by delivering lead generation programmes, from email campaigns and webcasts to events sponsorship programmes

Key outcomes:

- Managed logistics, promotions, and elements of all EMEA events and events sponsorship, including attendance to tradeshows or Extensis own events (from live webinars to in house events).
- Successfully delivered all aspects of a one-day live event with a budget averaging £15k Extensis Portfolio
 Heritage and Culture User Group meeting held at the National Library.
 - o Collected feedback from attendees which was mostly positive with attendees inquiring about next event.
 - o Secured three new customers, subsequently running a case study about experience with Extensis.
 - o Materialised landing page to follow-up with event attendees and Extensis subscribers.
- Optimised marketing development fund (MFD) for channel partners, heightening local brand exposure and increasing sales.

Avon Cosmetics & Mentaur Ltd., Northampton

2013 to 2014

Marketing Co-Ordinator (1) & Technologist Assistant (2), (May 2014 to Sep 2014 - 5 moths - short term contract)

Marketing & Communications Officer (3) (May 2013 to April 2014 – 1 year – maternity cover)

Contracted to two separate, consecutive roles to assist the marketing and business development teams.

Key outcomes:

- (1) Advanced online presence via content generation and graphic materials uploaded to website, whilst leveraging newsletter / social media platforms to boost email campaigns.
- (2) Delivered a range of administrative services, from data entry to organising photography samples, including new product flow, phase-out dates, and pagination.
- (3) Gained exposure and influenced public's perception of company by managing PR and media relations.
 - Modernised marketing collateral, including revamping magazine by writing engaging content and designing imagery / layout.
 - Identified strategic, offline marketing opportunities, utilising recruitment fairs, brochures, and internal client magazine to increase brand awareness to target audiences.

Page 4

Further experience in Marketing and Admin roles in Portugal

2007 to 2013

Marketing Assistant AGI, Portugal (02/2013 – 04/2013 - short term contract position)

Digital Marketing Assistant, COTEC, Portugal (02/2012 - 01/2013 - short term contract position)

Digital Marketing Assistant, Bonustable, Portugal (09/2011 – 01/2012 - short term contract position)

Marketing Co-Ordinator, Centro Medico da Praca (03/2008 – 08/2011 – permanent position)

Receptionist, Escola Inglesa (06/2007 – 12/2007 - short term contract position)

Education

CareerFoundry, UX Design Program, Online - Ongoing
Post - Graduate Diploma in Digital Marketing, Digital Marketing Institute, Ireland - 2019 (Merit-63%)

CAM Foundation – Award Unit: Web Analytics & Social Media Monitoring, Oxford College of Marketing, UK – 2018 (Merit-65%)

CAM Level 4 Diploma in Digital Marketing, London School of Marketing, UK - 2014

MSc in Marketing, Porto University, Portugal - 2011

BSc in Communications Sciences, Beira Interior University, Portugal – 2006 Study Abroad Programme in Spain as part of my BSc in Communication Sciences (six-months)

Technical Proficiencies

Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint) | Experienced User
Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, InDesign) | Experienced User
HubSpot | Content Marketing Certification, 2020 (81.7%)
WordPress | Basic User
HTML and Markdown coding languages | Intermediate User

Languages

Portuguese (native), English (fluent), Spanish (basic), French (basic), & German (basic)